{"data":{"site":{"pathPrefix":"/restaurant-inspections"},"postgres":{"establishment":[{"establishmentid":"5132","name":"Vertical Detroit","address":"1538 Centre St","zipcode":"48226","owner":"James J. Lufty","licenseNumber":"082648","licenseType":"Fixed Establishment","establishmentType":"Food Service Establishment","establishmentStatus":"Open","riskCategory":"High","reviewFrequencyDays":"180.0","coords":"-83.04729,42.33638","geojson":{"id":"5132","type":"Feature","geometry":{"type":"Point","coordinates":[-83.047286227,42.3363842250001]},"properties":{"name":"Vertical Detroit","owner":"James J. Lufty","address":"1538 Centre St","zipcode":"48226","license_type":"Fixed Establishment","risk_category":"High","license_number":"082648","establishmentid":"5132","establishment_type":"Food Service Establishment","establishment_status":"Open","review_frequency_days":"180.0","most_recent_license_date":"5/7/2018"}},"nearbyList":[{"establishmentid":"5189","name":"Dilla's Delight's LLC","address":"242 John R","zipcode":"48226"},{"establishmentid":"4317","name":"Colors","address":"311 E Grand River Ave","zipcode":"48226"},{"establishmentid":"4906","name":"Jose's Tacos, LLC","address":"218 E Grand River","zipcode":"48226"},{"establishmentid":"4427","name":"Steve's Detroit Deli","address":"212 E Grand River","zipcode":"48226"},{"establishmentid":"355","name":"Detroit Athletic Club","address":"241 Madison Ave","zipcode":"48226"},{"establishmentid":"3925","name":"La Casa De La Habana Detroit","address":"1502 Randolph","zipcode":"48226"},{"establishmentid":"5337","name":"I Luv Cheese","address":"1368 Broadway","zipcode":"48226"},{"establishmentid":"1680","name":"Michigan Opera Theater","address":"1526 Broadway St","zipcode":"48226"},{"establishmentid":"4106","name":"Detroit Seafood Market","address":"1435 Randolph","zipcode":"48226"},{"establishmentid":"1106","name":"Music Hall Center","address":"350 Madison","zipcode":"48226"},{"establishmentid":"4373","name":"Small Plates LLC","address":"1521 Broadway St","zipcode":"48226"},{"establishmentid":"322","name":"Twentieth Century Club, (Gem Theatre)","address":"333 Madison","zipcode":"48226"},{"establishmentid":"2614","name":"Detroit Beer Co.","address":"1529 Broadway St","zipcode":"48226"},{"establishmentid":"3404","name":"Vicente's Cuban Cuisine","address":"1250 Library St","zipcode":"48226"},{"establishmentid":"4912","name":"Punch Bowl Social-Detroit","address":"1331 Broadway","zipcode":"48226"},{"establishmentid":"4972","name":"Punch Bowl 360 Bar","address":"1331 Broadway","zipcode":"48226"},{"establishmentid":"4973","name":"Punch Bowl VIP","address":"1331 Broadway","zipcode":"48226"},{"establishmentid":"4844","name":"Centre Park Restaurant","address":"1407 Randolph","zipcode":"48226"},{"establishmentid":"4667","name":"Bert's on Broadway DBA Rockefellers","address":"1315 Broadway","zipcode":"48226"},{"establishmentid":"4957","name":"Cornerstone Barrel House","address":"1456 Woodward Ave","zipcode":"48226"}],"inspectionsByEstablishmentidList":[{"inspectionid":"43459","inspectionDate":"2018-09-11T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"violationCode":"4-501.114","violationDescription":"A chemical SANITIZER used in a SANITIZING solution for a manual or\r\nmechanical operation shall meet these limits or as otherwise approved: (P)\r\n\tChlorine        ppm           pH<10             pH<8\r\n\t\t      25              120 F              120 F\r\n\t\t      50              100 F              75 F\r\n\t\t     100              55 F               55 F\r\n                 Iodine           a concentration of between 12.5 and 25 ppm and minimum temp of 75 F and pH of 5 or less or meets manufacturer's specifications. (P)\r\n\r\n                Quats            minimum temperature of 75 F, hardness of 500 ppm or less and meet manufacturers use directions. (P)\r\n","violationType":"Priority","itemDescription":"Chlorine solution concentration","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Below 25 ppm","subProblem":"","location":"DISHWASHING ROOM","subLocation":"At the Dishwasher","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2018-09-11T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Provide correct concentration as stated above."},{"violationCode":"3-501.16","violationDescription":"Except during preparation, cooking, or cooling, or when time is used as the public health control POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD) shall be maintained:\r\n(A)  135ºF or above, except that roasts properly cooked and cooled may be held              at a temperature of 130ºF; or (P)\r\n(B)   At 41ºF or less (P)\r\n","violationType":"Priority","itemDescription":"Cold food item(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Stored above 41 degrees F","subProblem":"","location":"COOK LINE AREA","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2018-09-11T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Discard"},{"violationCode":"4-601.11","violationDescription":"(A) EQUIPMENT FOOD-CONTACT SURFACES and UTENSILS shall be clean to sight and touch. (Pf)\r\n(B) The FOOD-CONTACT SURFACES of cooking EQUIPMENT and pans shall be kept free of encrusted grease deposits and other soil accumulations. \r\n(C) NonFOOD-CONTACT SURFACES of EQUIPMENT shall be kept free of an accumulation of dust, dirt, FOOD residue, and other debris. \r\n","violationType":"Foundation","itemDescription":"Food-contact surface(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"With accumulation of debris","subProblem":"","location":"STORAGE AREA(S)","subLocation":"For the Equipment","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2018-09-11T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Keep clean."},{"violationCode":"6-301.12","violationDescription":"Each HANDWASHING SINK or group of adjacent HANDWASHING SINKS shall be provided with:\r\n(A) Individual, disposable towels; (Pf)\r\n(B) A continuous towel system that supplies the user with a clean towel;(Pf) or \r\n(C) A heated-air hand drying device.(Pf)\r\n(D) A hand drying device that employs an air-knife system that delivers high velocity pressurized air at ambient temperatures.(Pf)\r\n","violationType":"Foundation","itemDescription":"Sanitary hand drying provisions","subItem":"disposable, paper towels","problemDescription":"Not provided","subProblem":"","location":"PREP AREA(S)","subLocation":"At the Handsink","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2018-09-11T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Provide as required"},{"violationCode":"MFL289.2129","violationDescription":"Sec. 2129. (1) All of the following food establishments shall employ a minimum of 1 managerial employee who is currently certified under a personnel certification program accredited by the American national standards institute, utilizing the conference for food protection standards:  (a) A food service establishment that is not any of the following:    (i) Operating under a temporary food service establishment license.  (ii) A vending machine location.     (b) An extended retail food establishment.  (c) Operated within a retail grocery.  (2) An individual certified under subsection (1) shall be recognized with full faith and credit by the state and all local units of government throughout the state.  (3) The department may promulgate rules to do all of the following:  (a) Develop requirements for retail food establishments to follow when employing certified food safety managers or personnel.  (b) Set a reasonable date for compliance with the requirements under subdivision (a) taking into consideration existing local personnel certification requirements.  (c) Establish certification fees necessary to implement, maintain, and track certified individuals directly or by contract. The department may annually adjust the schedule of fees to provide that the fee charged is sufficient to cover the cost of the certification tracking program.  (d) Implement and enforce the requirements described in subdivision (a).    (4) The certification program developed by the American national standards institute, as it exists on April 1, 2008 , is incorporated by reference. The department may adopt updates to the certification program accreditation standards in subsection (1) by rule.     (5) This section does not prohibit any local legislative body from implementing a food handler program, an employee health certification program, or a manager certification program, if it is not in conflict with this section.","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Person-in-charge","subItem":"","problemDescription":null,"subProblem":"","location":"ESTABLISHMENT","subLocation":"","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":null},{"violationCode":"3-302.12","violationDescription":"Except for containers holding FOOD that can be readily and unmistakably recognized such as dry pasta, working containers holding FOOD or FOOD ingredients that are removed from their original packages for use in the FOOD ESTABLISHMENT, such as cooking oils, flour, herbs, potato flakes, salt, spices, and sugar shall be identified with the common name of the FOOD.","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Food item(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not identified","subProblem":"","location":"STORAGE AREA(S)","subLocation":"For the Bulk food bins","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":"2018-09-11T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Label containers with common name."},{"violationCode":"4-903.11","violationDescription":"Cleaned EQUIPMENT and UTENSILS, laundered LINENS, and SINGLE-SERVICE and SINGLE-USE ARTICLES shall be stored in an approved manner and location.\r\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Clean equipment/utensil(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not stored in self-draining position","subProblem":"","location":"STORAGE AREA(S)","subLocation":"For the Equipment","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":"2018-09-11T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Store in self-draining position."},{"violationCode":"3-304.12","violationDescription":"During pauses in FOOD preparation or dispensing, UTENSILS shall be stored:\r\n(A) In the FOOD with their handles above the top of the FOOD and the container;\r\n(B) In FOOD that is not POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS with their handles above the      top of the FOOD within containers or EQUIPMENT that can be closed, such as      bins of sugar, flour, or cinnamon;\r\n(C) On a clean portion of the FOOD preparation table or cooking EQUIPMENT\r\n(D)  In running water, such as dipper well.\r\n(E)  In a clean, protected location if the UTENSILS, such as ice scoops, are   used only with a FOOD that is not POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS; or\r\n(F)  In a container of water maintained at a temperature of at least 135° F.\r\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Dispensing utensil(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Improperly stored","subProblem":"To prevent contamination of food or food related items","location":"BACK AREA","subLocation":"At the Ice machine","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":"2018-09-11T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Store in manner that does not contaminate items"},{"violationCode":"6-501.12","violationDescription":"(A) PHYSICAL FACILITIES shall be cleaned as often as necessary to keep them clean.\r\n(B) Except spill cleanup, cleaning shall be done during periods when the least amount of FOOD is exposed such as after closing. ","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Physical facilities/structures","subItem":"ceiling","problemDescription":"Soiled","subProblem":"","location":"CEILING","subLocation":"","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Clean."}]},{"inspectionid":"40901","inspectionDate":"2017-11-21T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inCompliance":"No","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"violationCode":"3-501.16","violationDescription":"Except during preparation, cooking, or cooling, or when time is used as the public health control POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD) shall be maintained:\r\n(A)  135ºF or above, except that roasts properly cooked and cooled may be held              at a temperature of 130ºF; or (P)\r\n(B)   At 41ºF or less (P)\r\n","violationType":"Priority","itemDescription":"Hot food item(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Stored below 135 degrees F","subProblem":"","location":"HOT HOLDING AREA","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2017-11-21T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Store above 135 degrees F."},{"violationCode":"3-501.17","violationDescription":"(A)  READY-TO-EAT, POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD)  prepared and held refrigerated for more than 24 hours in a FOOD ESTABLISHMENT  shall be clearly marked at the time of preparation to indicate the date or day by which the FOOD shall be consumed. (Pf)\r\n(B)  A container of refrigerated, commercially prepared READY-TO-EAT POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD)  shall be clearly marked, at the time the original container is opened in a FOOD ESTABLISHMENT, to indicate the date or day by which the FOOD shall be consumed. (Pf)\r\n\r\nA date marking system that does not exceed 7 days, including date of preparation, or opening is to be used. (Pf)\r\n","violationType":"Foundation","itemDescription":"In house prepared ready-to-eat potentially hazardous  food(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Improperly date marked","subProblem":"","location":"COOLER","subLocation":"","corrected":"No","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Establishment shall provide a clear date marking system."},{"violationCode":"6-501.12","violationDescription":"(A) PHYSICAL FACILITIES shall be cleaned as often as necessary to keep them clean.\r\n(B) Except spill cleanup, cleaning shall be done during periods when the least amount of FOOD is exposed such as after closing. ","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Physical facilities/structures","subItem":"ceiling","problemDescription":"Soiled","subProblem":"","location":"CEILING","subLocation":"","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Clean."}]},{"inspectionid":"38599","inspectionDate":"2017-05-02T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"violationCode":"3-501.16","violationDescription":"Except during preparation, cooking, or cooling, or when time is used as the public health control POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD) shall be maintained:\r\n(A)  135ºF or above, except that roasts properly cooked and cooled may be held              at a temperature of 130ºF; or (P)\r\n(B)   At 41ºF or less (P)\r\n","violationType":"Priority","itemDescription":"Cold food item(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Stored above 41 degrees F","subProblem":"","location":"COOLER","subLocation":"At the DATE MARKING","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2017-05-02T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Store below 41 degrees F."},{"violationCode":"3-501.18","violationDescription":"A FOOD specified in ¶ 3-501.17(A) or (B) shall be discarded if it:  \r\n    (1) Exceeds the temperature and time combination specified in ¶ 3-501.17(A),              except time that the product is frozen; (P)\r\n    (2) Is in a container or PACKAGE that does not bear a date or day; (P) or\r\n    (3) Is appropriately marked with a date or day that exceeds a temperature and              time combination as specified in ¶ 3-501.17(A). (P)  \r\n\r\n","violationType":"Priority","itemDescription":"Ready to eat, potentially hazardous food(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Beyond consume by date","subProblem":"","location":"COOLER","subLocation":"At the Past date food","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2017-05-02T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Discard."},{"violationCode":"4-302.14","violationDescription":"A test kit or other device that accurately measures the concentration in mg/L of SANITIZING solutions shall be provided. (Pf)\r\n","violationType":"Foundation","itemDescription":"Sanitizer test kit","subItem":"chlorine","problemDescription":"Not provided","subProblem":"","location":"SANITIZER","subLocation":"At the Test strips","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2017-05-11T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Provide as required"},{"violationCode":"6-501.12","violationDescription":"(A) PHYSICAL FACILITIES shall be cleaned as often as necessary to keep them clean.\r\n(B) Except spill cleanup, cleaning shall be done during periods when the least amount of FOOD is exposed such as after closing. ","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Physical facilities/structures","subItem":"ceiling","problemDescription":"Soiled","subProblem":"","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"At the Ceiling tile(s)","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Keep clean."}]},{"inspectionid":"36682","inspectionDate":"2016-10-05T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"violationCode":"4-501.114","violationDescription":"A chemical SANITIZER used in a SANITIZING solution for a manual or\r\nmechanical operation shall meet these limits or as otherwise approved: (P)\r\n\tChlorine        ppm           pH<10             pH<8\r\n\t\t      25              120 F              120 F\r\n\t\t      50              100 F              75 F\r\n\t\t     100              55 F               55 F\r\n                 Iodine           a concentration of between 12.5 and 25 ppm and minimum temp of 75 F and pH of 5 or less or meets manufacturer's specifications. (P)\r\n\r\n                Quats            minimum temperature of 75 F, hardness of 500 ppm or less and meet manufacturers use directions. (P)\r\n","violationType":"Priority","itemDescription":"Chlorine solution concentration","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Below 100 ppm","subProblem":"And/or water temperature less than 55 degrees f","location":"3 COMPARTMENT SINK AREA","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2016-10-05T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Provide correct concentration as stated above."},{"violationCode":"4-501.114","violationDescription":"A chemical SANITIZER used in a SANITIZING solution for a manual or\r\nmechanical operation shall meet these limits or as otherwise approved: (P)\r\n\tChlorine        ppm           pH<10             pH<8\r\n\t\t      25              120 F              120 F\r\n\t\t      50              100 F              75 F\r\n\t\t     100              55 F               55 F\r\n                 Iodine           a concentration of between 12.5 and 25 ppm and minimum temp of 75 F and pH of 5 or less or meets manufacturer's specifications. (P)\r\n\r\n                Quats            minimum temperature of 75 F, hardness of 500 ppm or less and meet manufacturers use directions. (P)\r\n","violationType":"Priority","itemDescription":"Quaternary ammonia solution","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Below 100 ppm","subProblem":"","location":"3 COMPARTMENT SINK AREA","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2016-10-05T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Provide correct concentration as stated above."},{"violationCode":"4-302.14","violationDescription":"A test kit or other device that accurately measures the concentration in mg/L of SANITIZING solutions shall be provided. (Pf)\r\n","violationType":"Foundation","itemDescription":"Sanitizer test kit","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not provided","subProblem":"","location":"3 COMPARTMENT SINK AREA","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2016-10-10T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Provide as required"},{"violationCode":"2-103.11","violationDescription":"The PERSON IN CHARGE shall ensure that employees, practices and policies are in compliance with the code. (Pf) \r\n","violationType":"Foundation","itemDescription":"Person-in-charge","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not ensuring compliance","subProblem":"","location":"PERSON IN CHARGE","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2016-10-10T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Person-in-charge must ensure compliance with items listed above."},{"violationCode":"4-302.12","violationDescription":"(A) FOOD TEMPERATURE MEASURING DEVICES shall be provided and readily accessible for use in ensuring attainment and maintenance of FOOD temperatures as specified under Chapter 3. (Pf)   \r\n(B) A TEMPERATURE MEASURING DEVICE with a suitable small-diameter probe that is designed to measure the temperature of thin masses shall be provided and readily accessible to accurately measure the temperature in thin FOODS such as MEAT patties and FISH filets. (Pf)\r\n","violationType":"Foundation","itemDescription":"Food thermometer(s)","subItem":"probe","problemDescription":"Not provided","subProblem":"","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2016-10-10T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Provide as required"},{"violationCode":"4-501.11","violationDescription":"EQUIPMENT shall be maintained in a state of repair and condition that meets the requirements of the code.\r\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Equipment","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Broken","subProblem":"","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":"2016-10-10T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Repair/replace."}]}]}]}},"pageContext":{"eid":"5132"}}